Nasimi Guliyev

Richmond, VA 23220

Phone: (503) 268-3766 | Email: guliyevns@outlook.com

LinkedIn: https://github.com/guliyev | GitHub: https://github.com/guliyev

Portfolio: http://www.guliyev.com

SUMMARY

Front-End Web Developer leveraging a background in engineering. Known among colleagues for strong wit and attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project. Excited to leverage skills as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team in order to build better experiences for users.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End: React, JavaScript, jQuery, Web APIs, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, IndexedDB **Back End**: Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MongoDB, Mongoose, mLab, MySQL, Sequelize, and Passport

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Richmond, Richmond, VA 2019 – 2020 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor's Degree in Science: Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry University. 2007 – 2011 Graduated from Faculty of Manufacturing Automation Processes, with specialization in Automation Engineering.

EXPERIENCE

Ellwood Thompson's

05.08.2018 – present

Sales Associate

Richmond, VA

Sales Associate with a locally owned organic market. Responsible for dealing with customer questions about the products and discovering needs and making recommendations to build and close sales.

- Create meaningful relationships with customers to ensure they will come back.
- Maintain high-level knowledge of store products to address customer questions and concerns.
- Helped an average 70 plus customers daily.

"Azeravtovol" OJSC

2017 - 2018

Front End Developer

Baku, Azerbaijan

- Proficient use of web mark-up, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, jQuery for building internal application.
- Developed, maintained, and improved internally facing software products to collect, process, and distribute information in support of the operation of large-scale transportation project.

• Collaborated with the product and UX Design team to design and implement product features in a fast-paced environment following agile development methodologies.

"Bank of Baku" OJSC

2012 - 2017

QA Manual Tester

Baku, Azerbaijan

- Collaborated with development, QA and business analysts in identifying test script requirements.
- Reported and analyzed test results and discovered defects.
- Experience in testing the application across different Browsers.
- Supports the functional test teams in their execution of test cases.

PROJECTS

TrendingBot App | trendingbot.com | trendingbot-code.com

- TradingBots application targets high-volume traders who want to simplify trading through a nimble interface and customizable analytics. Our application allows users to set up pre-established strategies for getting trading tips.
- Core responsibilities: UI design; HTML and CSS development; shared responsibility for JavaScript
- **Technologies used:** Bootstrap, Materialize Corporate ,Jquery UI, MomentJS, amCharts, IEX api, Stock news API

Valentinos Restaurant | valentinos.com | valentinos-code.co

- Valentino restaurant application allows the restaurant to run a paperless operation and allows managers to evaluate sales composition and monitor the efficiency of the operation real-time.
- Core responsibilities: Express routing and Sequelize queries for post routes; Heroku and JawsDB deployment
- **Technologies used:** Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, JavaScript, jQuery, Heroku, JawsDB, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Chart.js, Passport

Construction Helper | constructionhelper.com | constructionhelper-code.com

- The main purpose of the application is to help users to create their project seamlessly and post it by leaving their contact information, and during a limited time to get an offer in order to realize the project.
- Core responsibilities: : UI design; Back-end development with Express, Node.js, and MongoDB; Shared responsibility for front-end React
- **Technologies used:** MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js), Mongoose, JavaScript, CSS,HTML, Heroku, mLab,